你不是要拋下我一日游吧
Not going on a day trip without me, are you?
前情提要
這次不是一日游  小伙伴
Not a day trip this time, partner.
我不能賣你票
I can't sell you a ticket.
等下  別啊  喂
Eh... Hey, hang on, no... Hello!
給我看看你護照  這個失效了
Can I see your passport? This is invalid.
半死癥患者出行證明
我怎么拿到證明
How do I get a certificate?
完成半死癥患者回饋計劃
By completing the PDS Give Back Scheme.
你告訴他  他不需要離開
Tell him he doesn't have to leave.
我們會改變這里
We're going to change things around here.
我們不都一塊擦窗戶的嗎
We're washing windows together.
海莉催我趕緊付賬單  伙計
Haley's pressuring me about bills, mate.
伙計
Mate?
我是個小企業主  我為什么要參與這個計劃
I'm a small-business owner, why do I have to do this scheme?
你也是個半死癥患者
You're also a PDS sufferer.
你以為我當初為什么會復生啊
Why do you think I came back from the dead in the first place?
這樣我就能和小潔在一起了
It's so me and Jem Walker can be together.
進去  進去  進去
In, in, in!
求你了  求你了
Please, please!
先知怎么說
What did the Prophet say?
他說  "去第一次復生的發生地
He said, "Go to the place where the first rose,
找到他們"
and seek them out."
這里沒有什么好留戀的了
There's just nothing for me here.
還有我
There's me.
我的柯爾特
My Colt!
那可是歷史紀念  小戰士
That's a piece of history, that, soldier.
不該落在庸人手里
It deserves to be in the right hands.
恭喜海莉和弗雷迪
現在有請新婚燕爾的普雷斯頓夫婦
Here we present the happy couple, Mr and Mrs Preston!
對沒來現場的人有什么話說
Any words for the people at home?
我妻子和我很高興
My...wife and I are gratified
能有這么多衷心祝福我們的人來到這里
that so many kind well-wishers could be here
和我們一同慶祝我們的婚禮
to join the celebration of our nuptials.
我們希望你們能過得愉快
A simply wonderful time is wished by us to you.
你們今天過得不錯是嗎
You guys had a good day, then?
最好的一天
The best.
我人生中最好的一天
The best day of my life.
打擾一下  打擾一下
Excuse me. Excuse me!
你有完沒完
Have you not finished yet?
你們有什么未來計劃
What does the future hold for you two?
馬格洛夫
Magaluf!
六天  半食宿  包機票
Six days, half-board, flights included.
真煩人
Bloody thing.
你們今天過得不錯是嗎
You guys had a good day, then?
最好的一天
The best.
我人生中最好的一天
The best day of my life.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
你有完沒完
Have you not finished yet?!
你表響了  打針了嗎
I heard your watch. Have you had your shot?
馬格洛夫
Magaluf!
弗雷迪  你不該看這個
Freddie, no. You shouldn't be watching this.
蜜月之后呢
After the honeymoon?
沒計劃
No plans.
有了她我還需要什么計劃
Who needs plans when I've got this one?
我愛你
I love you.
你說什么
What was that?
我愛你
I love you.
再說一遍  我聽不清
Say it again. I...couldn't hear.
我愛你
I love you!
我們還是有些計劃的吧
We have got some plans, though.
是嗎
Do we?
-先要生幾個孩子  -海莉  你在下面嗎
- Yeah, first off, some kids... - Haley, you down there?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
回床上睡覺嗎
You coming back to bed?
好  就回
Yeah. Yeah.
第二季  第三集
復生
人人影視英劇社傾情奉獻
翻譯  艾瑞卡
unundu
CiciXT
肉松富士
愛卿遛小鳥
木淺薰
小shy
雪莉的苦艾
特別嗚謝  POTO的小飯桶
時間軸
寶寶  Kallen  今
校對  安然若水
后期  寶寶
總監  安然若水
小潔
Jem?
我們來這干什么
What are we doing here?
我們該來的不是這
This isn't where we're supposed to be.
-我們得告訴別人  -不  不用
- We've got to tell someone. - No, we don't.
我才不回家
I'm not going in there.
我要去告訴別人我的所作所為
I want to go and tell what I did.
我們誰都不說
We're not saying anything to anyone.
我殺了亨利
I killed Henry.
來  看著我
Right, look at me.
你進去  表現正常點
You go in, be normal,
什么都不說
say nothing.
能睡就睡一會兒
Try and get some sleep if you can.
不會有事的
Everything's going to be all right.
小潔
Jem.
-小潔  你沒事吧  -什么
- Jem, are you all right? - What?
沒事
Yeah, fine.
不想面對爸媽是嗎
Didn't want to face them, eh?
某人今晚玩得不錯嘛
Someone had a good night.
是啊
Yeah.
我去的那個派對也挺有意思
The party I went to was pretty interesting, too.
有人跟我講到你
Oh, your name came up earlier.
亨利·蘭思德
Henry Lonsdale.
我覺得他對你有意思
I think he might have a little thing for you.
爸媽沒等我們
They didn't wait up.
感覺怪怪的  是吧
Feels a bit weird, doesn't it?
晚安
Night.
早上好  馬丁女士  喝茶嗎
Morning, Ms Martin. Cup of tea?
喝茶嗎
Cup of tea?
現在有點忙
Just in the middle of something.
那我就放你門外了啊
Leaving it outside your door, then.
現在你只需等待
Now, just you wait.
一切都會水到渠成
Everything's going to be perfect.
我發誓我會做好的
I promised I'd make it right.
早餐好啦
It's ready.
天吶  看看我
Oh, Christ, would you look at me?
我在看你
I am.
很漂亮
It's a good look.
高端專業人士
Top-end professional.
老天  你討厭你的手提箱
Oh, God, you hate your briefcase.
你是對的  不用給我面子  太不搭了
You do, it's fine, it's completely the wrong thing.
我留著發票呢  會退回去的
I've kept the receipt, I'll take it back.
我很喜歡  好嗎
I love it, OK?
只是我討厭被人通知
It's just that if someone had told me
在二十八歲生日當天要去上數據管理課
I'd be spending my 28th birthday on a data management course...
是啊  因為他們發現了你的潛質
Yeah, cos they spotted your potential, is why.
或者是他們注意到我眼中
Yeah, or they noticed the last glimmer of hope
最后一線希望消失了
disappear from my eyes.
他們可能要高升你呢
They're probably grooming you for a big promotion.
換我就會
I would.
我會讓你做地區經理
I'd make you regional manager.
那地區經理都做些什么
And what does a regional manager do?
使喚別人
Bosses people about.
你不會喜歡的
You wouldn't like it.
你看到我的鞋了嗎  海莉
Have you seen my shoes, Haley?
跟其他鞋一起在鞋柜里
They're in the shoe cupboard. With the shoes.
腦子跟篩子似的
Brain like a sieve.
在這家里可不能亂放東西啊
Can't leave anything down in this place.
這叫系統整理  弗雷迪  你也該試試
It's called a system, Freddie, you should give it a go some time.
我會寫在待辦事項里的  埃米
I tell you what, put it on my to-do list, Amir.
他們今天是安排你去搭圍欄嗎  弗雷迪
So, have they got you on the fence today, Freddie?
可能吧  至少是室外的活兒
Probably. At least it's outdoors.
我不喜歡跟那么多僵尸擠在一塊兒
I don't fancy being cooped up with that rotter crowd.
當然了  你跟他們完全不同
Of course, you'd have nothing in common with them.
好豐盛的早餐啊
Posh breakfast?
因為什么啊
What's that in aid of?
我會六點到家  把牛排煎上
I'll be home by six and I'll get the steaks on.
靠
Shit!
在家過生日真的沒事嗎
Are you sure you're OK with a night in?
沒事的
Yeah, of course I am.
別聽她的  埃米
Don't listen to her, Amir.
我們分開前  她生日我們總會出去慶祝
When we were married, we always went out on her birthday.
那次我們把自制雞尾酒點了
That time we nearly burnt down the Legion,
差點把軍團酒吧燒成平地
setting those made-up cocktails on fire.
還有去惠特比旅行  這才叫過生日嘛
And Whitby. Now, That was a birthday.
英國海濱小城
只不過我們沒能去到惠特比  對吧
Only we never got as far as Whitby, did we?
我們因為行為不檢點被趕下了火車
We got kicked off the coach for lewd behaviour.
那么...
Right, then...
還有那年在加里媽媽家  沒有泳池的泳池派對
And Gary's mum's place that year. The pool party with no pool.
多美好的夜晚  你穿著那身比基尼
What a night! And you in that bikini.
又脫了那身比基尼
Well, you out of that bikini.
怎么了
What?
我們只是在回憶往事  跟你無關
We're only reminiscing. You've done all right out of it.
你總不能連回憶都不許我吧
You can't begrudge a bloke a few fond memories.
不  我受不了了
No...I'm not having it.
埃米
Amir...
-我做什么了  -夠了  我認真的
- What am I doing? - It's enough now. I'm serious.
你說你會跟他說的
You said you'd say something.
說啊
Say something.
行吧  那我說
Fine, I will.
時間到  弗雷迪  抱歉  伙計
Time's up, Freddie. Yeah, sorry, mate.
你從治療中心回來時  我們說好你住兩個月的
Two months we said when you came back from the treatment centre.
那天是八月九號
August 9th that was.
今天是十二月六號  也是海莉的生日
December 6th today. Haley's birthday, by the way.
這我知道
Yeah, I-I know that.
我們再給他一點時間  等他把車賣了吧
How about we just give him until he's sold the car?
我之后再補你禮物
I'll give you a present later on.
我每次跟你說這件事  你都這么說
Every time I talk to you about it, it's the same thing.
你覺得內疚  他還沒準備好
You feel guilty, he's not ready,
他得把車賣了才能有一點存款
he's got to sell that bloody car to get a deposit together.
他根本就沒把車拿去掛牌出售  對吧
He's not even put the car on the market, have you?
是的
Right...
海莉  你到底想不想讓他走
Haley? Haley...do you want him gone or not?
埃米
Amir!
今天要上班嗎
Working today?
如果你要這么叫的話
If that's what you want to call it.
我...
Well, I, er...
你知道你有些疑慮
I know you've had your misgivings,
我做了些調查
but I've been doing some research
也許多少能幫你釋惑
I think may allay them somewhat.
調查新鮮事
You can always trust the lunatic fringe
總要靠狂熱分子  是吧
to run down the new thing, can't you?
這是壓迫  沒用的
No, it's oppression, it'll never work.
從半死癥患者到總裁
這個人呢  你覺得她看著像受壓迫的嗎
What about her? Does she look oppressed to you?
這里寫著她有管理潛質
It says here she's got management potential.
我不知道  爸
I don't know, Dad.
這項計劃才施行了幾天
I mean, the scheme's only been running for a couple of days.
早期而已
Early days.
我就是這意思
My point in a nutshell.
這里  "回饋計劃贏家"
Here. "Give Back Scheme a winner."
"珀爾·品特的人生箴言"
"Pearl Pinder's pearls of wisdom."
我們知道你想離開  孩子  你會的
We know you want to get away, son. Well, you will.
但同時  讓自己忙一點也好
Just, in the meantime, it's good to stay busy.
避免你胡思亂想
Keep your mind from going in on itself.
早上好  親愛的
Morning, love.
要玉米片嗎
Cornflakes?
不用了  爸
You're all right, Dad, ta.
不要嗎  我請客哦
No? I'm buying.
早餐是一天之中最重要的一餐
Breakfast - most important meal of the day.
-吃點早餐  -你得吃早餐  這樣才有力氣
- Have something. - You have to have something. Set you up.
是啊  我五年前吃的早餐  還飽著呢
Yeah, it's true. I ate breakfast five years ago, still full.
我不餓  謝了
Not hungry, thanks.
今天過得愉快  小潔
Have a good day, Jem.
我愛你們
I love you.
奇跡又出現了
Wonders never cease.
早上好  沃克一家
Morning, Walkers!
小潔對我可熱情了
Jem's warming up to me.
她出門的時候與我熱情地擦肩而過了
Nice welcoming brush past on her way out.
她可能只能承受這么點時間吧
Only so long she could resist, I suppose.
畢竟這姑娘是活人
After all, girl's only human.
你怎么還穿著睡衣
Why are you still in your sleep attire?
回饋計劃可不會
Give Back Scheme's not
自己乖乖聽話的
going to subjugate us on its own, you know.
我幫他換衣服
I'll help him with his clothes.
事情很麻煩吧
Terrible business.
你說什么
I'm sorry?
藍色赦"面"襲擊
Blue Oblivious attack.
是赦免
Oblivion.
我朋友芭芭拉的女兒克洛伊在上學
My friend Barbara, her daughter Chloe is at school.
據克洛伊所說  學齡半死癥患者都瘋迷這個
According to Chloe, all the PDS youngsters are at it.
簡直是潮流
It's the in thing.
還有登錄那個網站
Logging on to that website, too.
"為第二波復生做好準備
"Get ready for the second Rising.
"別用藥了  屠殺家人吧"
"Go off your drugs and slaughter your family."
這些信息對于
I mean, what sort of message
思想不成熟的小孩太有害了
is that giving out to impressionable minds?
你說得很對
You raise some excellent points.
就告訴你一聲  我讓克萊夫把康妮的網線拔了
Just so you know, I've had Clive unplug Connie's dial-up.
還是安全至上
Better be on the safe side.
我們可不想再來一波復生
Last thing we need is a second Rising.
第一波帶來的麻煩還不夠多嘛
As if there weren't enough bother with the first.
你那晚看到了什么  桑德拉
What did you see that night, Sandra?
我不想談這個
It's not something I like to talk about.
回想起痛苦的往事  你明白的
Brings back distressing memories. I'm sure you appreciate.
不過我依然覺得
Still, I think it's valuable
聽到關于復生的回憶很重要
to hear people's memories of the Rising.
我當時睡著了
I was asleep.
克萊夫也是  難以置信吧
So was Clive, would you believe?
從頭到尾都在睡覺
Slept through the whole thing.
門鈴響了
That's the doorbell.
你好  瑪克辛·馬丁在嗎
Yes? Maxine Martin here?
來找你的
It's for you.
-你是國會議員嗎  -是
- Are you the MP? - Yeah.
我是來自首的
I've come to hand myself in.
看到你昨晚在和我蒙說話
Saw you and Mymon were nattering away last night.
-我蒙  -我的西蒙
- Mymon? - My Simon.
而且非常親密
In very close conference.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
得體的家常聊天
Proper old chinwag.
我的名字不會在某個時候出現了吧
Don't suppose at any point the name of a certain me came up?
別磨蹭了  告訴我他說了我什么
Oh, stop dragging it out and tell me what he said about me!
你知道
Oh, you know...
什么
What?
我的眼睛
My eyes.
是主要說我迷人心魄的眼睛嗎
Was it mainly my hypnotic eyes?
都是你的好處
Yeah, all good stuff.
不是我的身體吧
Not body parts?
我的雙乳  我的臀部
My breasts? And my derriere?!
下流的禽獸
Filthy animal.
我們是開始也是結束
We are the first and the last.
我們曾經死去  如今已然復生
We are those that liveth and were dead
看  我們將永生
and behold, we are alive for ever more...
手握掌控生死的鑰匙
And have the keys of hell and death in our hands.
昨晚派對沒看到你
Didn't see you at the party last night.
因為我沒去
That's cos I wasn't there.
你該來的  派對棒極了
You should've come. It was amazing.
我有更重要事要做  親愛的
Better things to do, love.
什么事
Like what?
-改變我的生活  -酷
- Like changing my life. - Cool.
不過  那是我們在做的
No, that's what we're doing.
不是去參加僵尸狂歡派對
I didn't mean by hanging out at rotter raves,
而是改變我自己
I meant fixing the one I've got.
你怎么了
What's wrong with it?
糟得不能再糟了
Took a turn for the worse.
什么時候
When?
也許是我開著妻子的車
Probably around the time I got killed
撞死在一棵行道樹上的時候
driving my mate's car into a passing tree.
你笑什么
Why are you smiling like that?
因為
Because...
你還不明白
You don't see it yet.
我們死的時候  我們得到了恩賜
When we died, we were given a gift.
這樣么
Were we, yeah?
所以在地下腐爛的兩個星期
So those two weeks rotting under the ground,
我應該為此發感謝卡呢
I should be sending thank-you cards.
在狂暴狀態下流浪了幾年
And the roaming the Earth in a rabid state for years
被抓住后送到治療中心
and being captured and sent to a treatment centre
回家卻發現我妻子和房地產代理搞在一起
only to come home to find my wife shacked up with an estate agent
和他躺在我們的床上
and lying with him in our bed
我卻在隔壁客房
while I'm next door
和他的黑膠唱片集作伴
in the guest room with his vinyl collection...
我們說的是同一種恩賜嗎
Is that all part of the same gift, is it?
好極了
Very nice.
我剛開始干點事業
And when I start a little business,
為自己的前途著想
trying to build something for myself,
結果全被奪走
only to have that taken away from me and all,
我被迫來這白干活  還是和一群
so I have to come here and work for nothing with a bunch of...
無意冒犯  奇怪的死人
..No offence...weird dead people.
謝謝你  非常感謝
Thank you. Thanks a lot
我太感激你了
You shouldn't have.
你會明白的
You'll see.
今早沒看到你
I missed you this morning.
我得幫個笨蛋過馬路來這
Oh, I had to help Dozy here crossing the road.
下次出去告訴我一聲  好嗎
Well, you let us know where you're going next time, OK?
-你是不是擔心死了  -是的
- Oh, were you worried sick? - I was, yeah.
我不在身邊他就不知所措了
He goes to pieces when I'm not around.
-好了  -這可是個夠長的擁抱
- Hey...OK. - This is a long hug.
只為特別人士準備的特別擁抱嗎
Is it a special hug just for special people?
當然是了
Of course it is.
對不起了吉倫  只為特別人士
Sorry, Kieren, it's just for special people.
所有人聽好了  我們開始
OK, everyone, let's get this started.
麻煩找位子坐下  非常感謝
If you wouldn't mind taking a seat, thank you very much.
坐下好嗎
If you'd just like to take a seat.
謝謝
Thank you.
請坐下  好嗎  謝謝
If you'd just like to...take a seat. Thank you.
都坐下了
You all right?
迪恩
Dean?
布萊恩·康寧漢  康妮·福尼斯
Brian Cunningham, Connie Furness,
佐伊·凱利  福尼斯旅店
Zoe Kelly, Furness B&B.
沃克和蒙洛  全科醫生診所
Walker and Monroe, GP surgery.
剩下的人  回去修柵欄
Rest of yous, back on t'fence.
-福尼斯旅店  -是的
- Furness B&B? - Yeah.
我那個兒媳婦
That daughter-in-law of mine's
找到了免費的女仆  是不
got herself free chambermaids, has she?
想讓我清理下水道里的頭發
Thinks she can make me take the hair out of plugholes?
我生在那房子  死在那房子
I lived and died in that house.
那你知道該去干什么  對吧
You'll know your way around, then, won't you?
艾米·戴爾
Amy Dyer,
你留在這
you're to stay here.
-名字  -杰瑞·李
- Name? - Jerry Lee.
-名字  -羅伊·麥克魯
- Name? - Rory McCallum.
-名字  -大衛·紐波特
- Name? - David Newport.
迪恩  伙計  你得讓我開個小差
Dean, mate, you've got to get me out of here.
你想起來
Remember some windows
要背著人去擦玻璃  是嗎
need washing behind someone's back, have you?
迪恩  我說了我很抱歉  不過
Oh, Dean... I said I was sorry, just...
我得溜個號
I need some time away.
我是來監管工作的  不是批假條的
I'm here to supervise work, not give time off.
都在這了  我掙的每一分錢
That's all of it. Everything I earned.
你是唯一的股東了
I'll make you sole shareholder.
給人擦玻璃
What good's a window-cleaning business
不掙錢還擦什么勁
when you lot are cleaning folks' windows for nothing?
要是我是你  我就在股東周年大會再說
I'd bring it up at the AGM, if I was you.
給我半小時  求你了  很重要
Give us a half-hour. Please, it's important.
十分鐘
Ten minutes.
加里和這事無關
Gary had nothing to do with it.
我干的
It was me.
我要他帶著我  可我自己跑開了
I made him take me with him and I went off on my own.
之后你殺了亨利·蘭思德
And you shot Henry Lonsdale?
他是我們班上的
He was in my class.
他葬禮上我還念了首詩
I read a poem out at his funeral.
哪兒
Where?
什么
What?
他的葬禮在哪辦的
Where was his funeral?
諾頓
Roarton.
走
Come on.
你和艾米到底是什么情況
What are you doing with Amy?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我和艾米沒有情況
I'm not doing anything with Amy.
我是說
I mean...
她覺得你們倆已經算是在一起了
she thinks the two of you are involved.
你沒有試圖糾正她
And you're not doing anything to put her right.
你一直在誤導她
You keep leading her on.
我知道你對艾米非常了解
I know you're the big Amy expert
吉倫  但是
and everything, Kieren, but...
一旦艾米認定了什么念頭
once Amy gets an idea in her head,
其他人是沒有辦法讓她打消這個想法的
there's nothing anyone can do to get it out of it. OK?
我也很關心她
I care about her, too, you know.
非常關心
A lot.
吉倫
Kieren...
艾米是那種需要愛意關懷的人
Amy is someone who needs to see that she's loved.
所以我對她表現出愛意
So I show her love.
因為我確實愛她
Because I do love her.
不過不是戀人的愛而已
Just not like that.
就是這樣
So that's what's going on there.
我沒有誤導別人
I don't lead people on.
吉倫
Kieren!
沒趕上去巴黎的火車嘛
Never made it to the Paris train.
你好  羅素醫生
Hello, Dr Russo.
確實沒趕上
Afraid not, no.
太遺憾了
Desole, desole.
不過  很高興你留下來了
Still, good that you're here, though.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
是啊  我們的客人
Our guests, yes.
恐怕這種處置不是非常合理
Not an ideal arrangement, I'm afraid.
踱步是一種對壓力的反應
Pacing's a stress response.
那個受傷的  肌肉有顯著的退化
The one with the wound has considerable muscle deterioration.
當然了  味道很大
There's the smell, obviously.
蒂尼絲幾天前找過哈普倫和韋斯頓
Denise has been on to Halperin&Weston
希望能把他們給送走
for days trying to get them picked up.
直到今早還沒有回電  是吧蒂尼絲
Still not called back this morning, Denise, I presume?
援助服務和以前已經不一樣了
Service isn't what it used to be.
我聽說都被外包出去了
I hear they're outsourcing.
先生們
Gentlemen.
你們的工具
Your instruments.
好了  我們需要的是深度清潔
Now, what we want is a deep cleanse.
每一個角落和縫隙  都要清潔干凈
All the nooks and crannies. Really get in there.
要進籠子里嗎
In the cage?
不用擔心
Don't worry.
在神經替林起作用前他們都被打了鎮靜劑
They're sedated prior to the Neurotriptyline taking effect.
我想不會有任何問題的
There shouldn't be any problem, I wouldn't think.
蒂尼絲會教你們如何搞定它們
Denise will show you how to handle them,
-是吧蒂尼絲  -好的
- Won't you, Denise? - Will do.
好小伙
Good lad.
走廊那頭有個空儲物間
There's an empty cupboard down the hall.
可以把它們放在那里
You can put them in there.
停車
Stop here.
怎么了
What's going on?
為什么要停下
Why are we stopping?
我以為我們要去警察局
I thought we were going to the police.
帶我去看出事的地方
Show me where it happened.
為什么
Why?
因為我要看
Because I need to see.
所以  你們應該
So, what you want to be looking at
在這兩組軟件中選擇一組
is either of these two as your packages.
它們是市場領導者
They're the market leaders.
有人問我
Now, people say to me,
"為什么這兩組數據管理軟件
"Why are these two data management
"就是市場領導者"
packages your market leaders?"
我告訴他們
And I tell them...
"有八點充足的理由"
..."For eight very good reasons."
"第一
One...
誰啊
Who is that?!
你來干什么
What are you doing?
帶你去兜生日風
I'm taking you for a birthday spin.
怎么可能
You are not.
當然可能  我已經踩油門了  海莉
I am, too. I've put my foot down, Haley.
你不該把生日浪費在培訓班上
You're not spending your birthday on a training course.
來吧  這車的最后一次旅程
Come on, last voyage for this one.
明天就要簽賣車合同了
She's going in the paper tomorrow.
海莉  像我們以前那樣去兜風吧
Haley. Come for a spin like we used to.
你覺得以你的死法
If you think I'm getting in there with you,
我還會上你的車嗎
after how you died...
那給我上了非常有價值的一課
Taught me a very valuable lesson, that.
你再也找不到開車比我還安全的人了
You couldn't ask for a safer man behind the wheel.
你根本都不能開車  是吧
You're not even supposed to be driving, are you?
聽不見你
Can't hear you.
你有駕照嗎
Do you even have a licence?
引擎聲太吵了
It's the roar of the engine.
把你說話聲都壓過去了
It's drowning out what you're saying!
我不能就這樣離開  弗雷迪
I can't just leave, Freddie.
我聽得不太清楚
I'm not catching much,
但好像是什么
but it sounds like a lot
拒絕出去玩的一堆無聊的借口
of boring excuses not to have a good time.
像我說的  這么大的噪音我也不確定
Like I say, I can't be sure with all the noise.
我是不可能上你的車的
There is no way I'm getting in that.
這些事情都是命中注定的
There's rules about what's supposed to happen.
是我干的  我說了是我干的  我
I did it. I'm saying I did it. I...
我是想做正確的事情
I'm trying to do the right thing.
我只想趕快把這事解決了
I just want to get it over with.
怎么了
What is going on?
亨利·蘭思德是個殺人犯
Henry Lonsdale was a killer.
不可能  他連蒼蠅都不會傷害
No, he wouldn't hurt a fly.
他從墳墓里復生后說不定殺了多少人
He killed we don't know how many when he rose from the grave.
但是政府給他免罪金牌
And then he was given a free pass by the powers that be,
把這些都一筆勾銷了
told to put it behind him,
都給忘了
to forget about it.
亨利不會為他殺人而傷心
Henry didn't grieve over his kills.
你又為什么要難過呢
Why should you?
你冒著生命危險保護你的家庭  你的朋友
You risked your life to protect your family, your friends,
你的社區
your community.
你的免罪金牌在哪呢
Where's your free pass?
好了
Now...
在哪發生的
where did it happen?
這里  我
Here. I...
-你確定嗎  -我確定
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
那他在哪呢
Then where is he?
他在哪  小潔
Where is he, Jem?
你和埃米之間沒事吧
Things OK with you and Amir, then, are they?
是啊  不
Yeah, no, um,
他上班時給我打了電話  都說清楚了
he called me at work, so that's all sorted now.
我可不想看到你倆吵架
Don't like to see you two fight.
這個地方讓你想起點什么沒有
Ringing any bells for you, this place?
當然
Yes.
我還以為你那天太醉記不住呢
I thought you might have been too off your face to remember.
我記得
I remember.
太陽會在那里升起來
The sun would have come up just about there.
那天晚上就快要日出了
Nearly did it the night before.
但我又想  我在干什么  就要日出了
But then I thought, "What am I doing? It's got to be sunrise."
你確實知道找場合
Well, you do have a sense of occasion.
我單膝跪下
Got on one knee.
我看你就是四肢著地
Looked more like all fours from where I was standing.
我那時也醉了
Bit worse for wear, myself.
你說了愿意
You said yes.
給你戴上我的戒指
Put my ring on your finger.
那枚戒指
That ring!
啤酒罐拉環做的戒指
A ring-pull off an old beer can.
我知道那是什么  你個土鱉
I know what it was, you cheap sod!
但還是成了
Did the job, though.
我成了世界上最幸福的男人
Made me the happiest man on Earth.
天  我那時好幸福
God, I was happy.
原本就應該是那樣的
That's what it's supposed to be like.
我們還能重來  小海
It could be again, Hales.
別這樣
Don't.
我沒有
I'm not.
我只是說說
I'm just saying.
我該解釋一下...
I should explain...
誰去哪里工作不是我能決定的
that I've no influence over who goes where.
這是完全隨機的
It's an entirely randomised process.
你和那個披頭散發男
You and the straggly-haired one
早早起來就在紙上寫名字
get up early to write names on a piece of paper.
我覺得你可以在我不在的時候
What I thought was that you could manage the phones
接電話登記留言
and possibly take messages whilst I'm out.
然后你從帽子里抽出來
And then you pick them out of a hat.
因為一遇到你  我就發現...
Because when we met, I noticed...
我們相遇之時
Our meeting, yeah.
你是個聰明有教養的人
...that you're an intelligent and educated person.
我覺得你應該
And I thought you might
喜歡在能施展才干的地方工作
like to be somewhere you can exploit those skills.
所以不是完全隨機的
So not entirely randomised?
跟秘書差不多
It's like secretarial.
你想我做你的秘書嗎
You want me to be your secretary?
私人助理
Personal assistant?
你應該喜歡吧
You might like it.
不
No.
我不想跟你一起待在這里  我想和我朋友一起
I don't like being here with you. I'd rather be with my friends.
好吧  這邊來
Right. This way.
-你真準備這樣做嗎  -來
- You really going to do this? - Come on.
用控制棍
Use the guiding stick.
什么
The what?
照這個速度  我們得耗一整天
We'll be here all day at this rate.
拿著這個
You take this.
然后扣在這里
And you pop it on there.
然后拉他們  過來  過來
And then you guide them. Come on. Come on.
來拿著啊  這又不是我的工作
Take it, then. It's not my job.
你這樣可不行
You're just confusing him.
你得用力拉扯它
You need to give it a good old yank.
快過來
Come on!
放開他
Get away from him.
行  我們接手了  謝謝你  蒂尼絲
Right, we'll take it from here. Thanks, Denise.
他們沒事的
They'll be OK.
我會告訴羅素醫生她虐待他
I'll tell Dr. Russo she's mistreating them.
你以為羅素醫生面善  就會好心嗎
You think Russo's any better just cos he gives you a smile?
羅素也做不了什么  他也是棋子
Russo ain't going to do anything. He's part of the machine.
她也是  我們都是
Same as she is. Same as we are...
如果進展順利
If we go along with it,
我們能弄他們出去  在小屋里治好他們
we can get 'em out of here, medicate them back at the bungalow.
你根本不知道怎么照顧他們
You don't know the first thing about looking after 'em.
他們可能會發生意外
Anything could happen to 'em.
我不管  他們不會待在這里
I don't care. They'll be out of here.
他們幾天后就去治療中心
They'll be in the treatment centre in a few days,
那是安置他們的最佳地點
that's the best place for 'em.
你以為治療中心就能好些嗎
You think things are better in the treatment centre?
你不懂  你根本不了解那地方
You have no idea. You know nothing about that place.
聽著  我不像你還對這些人盲目期待
Look, I don't share your faith in these people being nice.
說真的  當你逐漸了解他們...
Really, when you get to know them...
會發現他們很殘忍
They're brutal.
我不想參與進來  別做傻事  行嗎
I don't want to be a part of it. Don't do anything stupid, OK?
行
Ok.
你在這里干什么
What are you doing here?
我來幫忙的
I'm here to help.
幫什么
What with?
給我看看尸體在哪兒
Show me where it is.
我告訴她了  加里
I told her, Gaz.
靠...小潔
Oh, for f... Jem!
我沒得選
I had to.
我批準巡邏
I sanctioned the patrol.
出了事也由我負責處理
It's my responsibility to handle the fallout.
尸體呢
Where's the body?
處理掉了
Dealt with.
燒了
I burned it.
骨頭分開埋的  沒人找得到
Bones are buried separate. No-one will find 'em.
他死過一次又復活了
He's had one funeral already.
必須處理干凈
It had to be done.
你真確定他死了嗎
Are you absolutely sure he was dead?
腦袋都打穿了
Back of his head were blown away.
看著也不像能再站起來走路了
Didn't look like something that were going to walk off.
來吧  我們該走了
Come on, we should go.
我說真的
I mean it.
把車開走  一去不回頭
Take the car and don't come back.
你答應過我不會走的
You promised you wouldn't do this.
這里有什么留戀的
What's keeping us here?
跟我私奔
Come with me.
去哪兒
Where to?
去個好地方
To a perfect place.
不找到不罷休
Just keep going till we find it.
-只要跟你一起就行  -弗雷迪...
- I'll be fine as long as I'm with you. - Freddie...
你也想走的  我看到你在看婚禮視頻
You want this, too. I saw you looking at the wedding video.
走吧  海莉  沒人有我們這么相愛
Come on, Haley, you never see two people that in love.
不會就這么結束的
It doesn't just end.
但那只是視頻
But that's just a video.
我們也不是一直都親密
Wasn't great all the time.
你真不是世界上最靠得住的男人
You weren't exactly the most reliable bloke in the world.
什么
What?
你那時根本不在我身邊  弗雷迪
You were never there, Freddie.
我割闌尾的時候
My appendix burst, and I
我只能打給我媽  讓她送我去醫院
had to call my mum to take me to the hospital.
很難受  很痛
That's hard. That stuff hurts.
-你應該告訴我  -我本來想的
- You should have said something. - I was going to.
我本來想的  但...
I was, and then...
沒必要了
I didn't have to.
聽著...
Look...
我會改的
I'll change.
我不是這個意思
That's not what I'm saying.
-我只是...  -跟我走吧  海莉
- All I'm saying... - Just come with me, Haley.
我不會那樣了  我發誓  我一定...
I won't be like that. I swear. I'll be...
加倍體諒你  還這么風趣
twice as considerate, and just as much fun.
來吧
Come.
我只想說  我得回去了
All I'm saying is, I've got to get back.
我跟他們說半小時就回
I told them I'd be half an hour.
這張不錯  他在笑
This one's nice. Smiling.
等人發現他時  他可能沒在笑
Might not be smiling when someone sees him.
你覺得哪張好
Which do you think?
用來做尋人啟事
For the missing poster.
我想我們可能
Look, I wonder if we might
有點操之過急了
be getting ahead of ourselves slightly.
我從昨天起就沒見過亨利了
I haven't seen Henry since yesterday.
我知道
Yes.
他當時說過要去哪里嗎
Did he mention at the time where he was going?
他一定是被學校里那些
I'm sure he was shaken up
流行的狂暴僵尸藥粉嚇壞了
by these rabid drugs going round school.
你知道亨利的  他很敏感
You know what Henry's like - he's very sensitive.
所以從昨天放學算起...
So, yesterday after school...
14小時了
14 hours.
現在還不能
Well, then... A person can't actually
正式確認他失蹤  除非等到48...
officially be considered missing until 48...
萬一他被人們口中的
What if he's been snatched by
那些極端分子帶走了怎么辦
some of these extremists people are talking about?
那些給小孩子吃藥的人
The ones giving kiddies drugs?
他們可能正需要亨利這樣的人
Probably needed someone like Henry.
他很有才
He's very able.
你當然會這么想
Of course you feel that way.
他的確很有才
And he is.
但還沒人舉報任何極端半死組織
But there haven't been any reports of extremist PDS groups
綁架其他半死癥患者
kidnapping other sufferers.
總得做點什么
Well, something needs doing.
等那議員女士來了我再來
I'll come back when that MP lady's in.
這是被詛咒者村莊  何事可以效勞
Village of the damned, how may I help you?
別這么接電話  好嗎
Please... please don't answer the phone like that.
他們早掛了
They hung up.
你冷嗎
You're cold.
我沒事
I'm fine.
蠢貨
Idiot.
第二十天將有筆試
Day 20 is the written exam.
通過筆試就能得到這個
Pass that, you get one of these.
數據管理基礎證書
Your certificate in data management essentials.
這是你打開職業大門的鑰匙
This is your passport to anywhere you want to go.
內部信息管理員
In-house data manager,
辦公室經理  部門協調員...
office manager, divisional coordinator...
你得找她再要點
You're going to have to ask her for some more.
我不放心自己直接跟她說話
I don't trust myself to talk to her.
去吧
Go on.
沒有清潔液了
We're out of cleaning fluid.
把鑰匙放回去
Put the keys back.
別多管閑事  吉倫
Mind your own business, Kieren.
你答應我不會惹事的
You said you wouldn't do anything.
我答應不會犯傻
I said I wouldn't do anything stupid.
我說過了別把我攪進來
I told you not to make me
你卻置之不理還利用我
part of it and you went ahead and used me.
你怎么都會攪進來的
You're part of this either way.
他們也是在利用你
You're being used by them.
我只是給你個機會改邪歸正
All I'm doing is giving you a chance to choose the right side.
我不會跟你同流合污的
I am not going to go along with you with this.
快把鑰匙放回去
Now put the keys back.
下次再掉的就是你的腦袋了
You'll forget your head next.
看來我一開始就看錯你了
I was wrong about you from the start.
-等等  -我跟你這種人沒話說
- Look... - I've got nothing to say to people like you.
我還以為你有點膽量  我想錯了
I thought there was something there. I was wrong.
還沒走
Still here?
是
Yes.
我被選區的事耽擱了
Held up by constituency business.
當然
Of course.
有個十幾歲的男孩貌似失蹤了
A teenage boy seems to have gone missing.
是我的一個鄰居  亨利·蘭思德
A neighbour of mine, actually. Henry Lonsdale.
-他昨晚沒回家  -半死患者還是活人
- He didn't come home last night. - PDS or living?
半死患者
PDS.
是嗎
Well, then.
他母親挺擔心的
His mother's quite upset.
我跟她說如果明天還沒消息
I told her that we'd start circulating these
我們就會發放尋人啟事
if there's still no sign by tomorrow.
不行
No.
她也許能派上些用場呢
I thought she could be of some use.
我們不這么做  讓她走
We don't do that. Get her out.
我怎么說
What should I say?
出去
Get out!
我們去會會你的這位鄰居吧
Now, then. Let's go and see this neighbour of yours.
蘭思德太太  我向您保證
Mrs. Lonsdale, I wanted to reassure you
我們已經盡全力
that everything is being done
尋找亨利了
to locate Henry's whereabouts.
小冊子上說  幾小時不服藥
Pamphlet says medication can wear off
藥效就會消失
within hours of a missed dose.
現在都快一整天了
It's been almost a day.
一般這種情況  最后都發現其實
Very often in cases like this, the young person will turn out
他們一直都待在朋友家呢
to have been at a friend's house all along.
你以為我沒問他的朋友嗎
Do you not think I've checked with his friends?
他不是夜宿朋友家了  菲利普
He's not on a sleepover, Philip.
如果我們知道亨利的想法和興趣
What might be useful is if we had an idea of Henry's thoughts
也許會有用
and interests.
這能幫你們找到他嗎
And that helps find them?
通常都很有幫助
Often.
他很受歡迎
He's very likeable.
他長得很精神
He's good looking.
亨利跟你談過復生的經歷嗎
Did Henry ever talk to you about the Rising?
這有什么關系
What's that got to do with it?
只是想排除一些可能性
We want to eliminate certain lines of inquiry.
有些更極端的半死神話傳說
There's a mythology amongst the more extreme PDS elements
認為第一批復生的人很特殊
that the first risen is in some way special,
所以應當有第二次復生
that they're needed to bring about a second Rising.
亨利就很特殊
Henry's special.
怎么個特殊法
How, exactly?
他有通靈能力
Psychic powers.
復生后就有了
Had 'em since he came back.
他不承認  但能看出來
He denied it but you could tell.
有時眼神迷離  我跟你說過的
Far-away look'd come over him. I told you, didn't I?
他提到過復生那晚看到什么了嗎
Did he talk about what he saw the night he rose?
基本都是腳
Oh, feet, mostly.
復生的時候各種走過他墓的人
People walking over his grave as he was coming up.
其他人  他不喜歡這樣
The other ones. Didn't like that.
非常在意自己的獨立空間
Always very protective of his personal space.
我說他被綁架了  你還不以為然
I said he were kidnapped. You pooh-poohed it.
被綁架的可能不大  但他很可能是
Kidnapping is highly unlikely. He may, however,
和一些極端分子有另類關系
have become involved with extremists by some other means.
我們必須考慮
We will have to look into
亨利被一些極端分子招募
the possibility that Henry was recruited
并參加了他們的集訓營的可能
and made his way to one of their training camps.
今晚就走  車庫等你  弗雷迪  吻你
小壽星
Hey, birthday girl.
這樣的事不能再發生了
Nothing like that can happen again.
好像我就喜歡大早上
And there was me looking forward to the next morning
去森林里肢解尸體似的
I could spend cutting up a body in a wood.
-好了就再來一杯  -好
- Another one of these when you're ready. - Right.
我也不想做什么危害你事業的事
Still, I don't want to do anything that might damage your career.
我不是這個意思
That's not it.
你們那些政客不都一樣嗎
All the same, you politicians.
我不在意這些
That's not what I'm concerned about.
維生黨在糾集小團體
Victus has been gathering intelligence on groups
打算帶來二次復生
looking to bring about another Rising.
他們認為需要先找到第一個復生的人
They believe they need to find the first risen before it can start.
所以要在諾頓村找
They're going to be looking in Roarton.
瘋了
Nut jobs.
不管第一個復生的是誰
Whoever this first risen is,
我們必須在其他人之前找到他
we want to find them before anyone else does.
這事必須被阻止
It needs to be stopped.
看來蘭思德家的男孩應該不重要
Now, as it turns out, this Lonsdale boy wasn't significant,
但我們也不能輕易冒這樣的險
but it's not the kind of risk we can take.
知道這有多重要了嗎
You see how important this is, don't you?
有點懂了
I'm getting there.
我今天去診所了
I went down to the GP surgery today.
那里有兩個狂暴態僵尸被鎖在籠子里
They had two rabids there, locked up in a cage,
他們將要送他們去治療
that they're going to send away for treatment...
去教育他們
so that they can teach them...
使他們能夠滿足
to integrate, to be what the...
活人的需要
living demand.
我看著他們就在想
I found myself looking at them...
他們得在籠子里關多久啊
wondering how long they were going to be in that cage.
你們又得在你們的籠子里關多久呢
How long are you going to be in your cage?
是什么束縛著真實的你們
What's stopping you from being the people you are,
把你們偽裝成過去的自己
instead of copies of who you used to be,
他們認為的過去的你
of what they tell you you have to be.
為什么不逃離  不展現自己的本真
Why don't you break free? Why don't you show yourselves?
當你真的做到時  我保證
Because when you do, when you finally do, I promise...
你們一定不會想念這些偽裝
you're not going to want to go back.
因為本真的你就是美麗的
Because you're going to be beautiful,
無暇的
you're going to be flawless.
你們才是未來
You're going to be the future.
誰先來
Who wants to go first?
明年絕不能過生日上課了
All right, next year -- no courses.
咱倆一起請個病假  痛快玩一場怎么樣
Let's both ring in sick, yeah? Have a proper blow-out?
恐怕你得忍受一下我的歌喉了
You're going to have to put up with my singing in a second.
閉上眼睛
Close your eyes.
-祝你生日  -埃米  我得跟你談談
- *Hap...* - Amir, I need to talk to you.
你還好嗎
Hey. Are you OK?
我聽說學校的事了
I heard about what happened at school.
現在沒心情  小吉
Not in the mood, K.
弗雷迪
Freddie.
海莉  門卡住了  從底下鉆進來吧
Haley! Um, the door jammed. You have to slide under.
我就知道你會來
Knew you'd come.
這是你計劃好的吧
Did you plan that?
你拿到啦
You got it, then?
-你居然留了它這么多年  -是吧
- Can't believe you kept it all this time. - I know.
其實它只是我在街上
OK, it might be more of a
找到的一個相像的代替品啦
replica that I found in the street than the actual one.
不管啦
Anyway...
請看
ta-da!
我們上路前應該先簡單慶祝一下生日嘛
Thought I'd lay on a little birthday bash before we hit the road.
希望能補償一下
Hope it might go some way
我沒陪你過的那些生日  說到彌補
to covering the ones I missed. Speaking of...
這是你的19歲生日禮物
That's your 19th.
這是22歲的
That's your 22nd.
還有25歲的
And that's your 25th.
是為這個死掉了  不過還記著呢
Dead for that one. Still counting it.
-這是除冰器吧  -沒錯
- De-icer. - Yeah.
這是卡普里使用手冊
And that's a Capri owner's manual.
可以放在車前座儲物箱的
It's an inside-the-glove-compartment theme.
看吧  我今后不會再忘記你生日了
See, now? I'm not forgetting any more birthdays.
我在改變  海莉  成為配得上你的人
I'm changing, Haley. I'm going to be the bloke you deserve.
我知道
Yeah. I, um...
我告訴了埃米我們中午見面的事
I told Amir about us meeting at lunch.
他怎么說
OK. How did he take that?
-弗雷迪  你得離開  -不要
- Freddie, you have to go. - No.
海莉  你不該這樣  是他說的嗎
Haley, that... This is the wrong choice. Just cos he says so.
這不是他的決定
It's not him saying it.
什么  這太傻了
What? This is stupid.
我們當時很幸福的
Hey... we were happy.
我們的確幸福
I know we were.
而且你總說我們還能回去
OK? And you keep telling me that I can have all that back.
今天我甚至開始相信了
And today, for the first time, I started to believe you.
我差點就和你走了  弗雷迪
I nearly went with you, Freddie.
-好啊  -不  我不再是過去的我了
- Well, good. - No. Listen, back then I was a different person.
我很愛過去的時光  很愛你
I loved that time. I loved you.
可是現在  我愛的是埃米
But... now I love Amir.
愛他什么
How?
我都半死了也比他有意思
Half dead and I've got more life in me than he's ever had.
你不愛他不代表我也不愛他
Just because you don't love him, it doesn't mean I don't, OK?
跟我走吧
Just come with me.
我會改的  我會變成熟
I'll change. I'll grow up.
你為什么要改變呢  你有了新生
Why would you do that? You've been given a new life.
完成回報活動你就可以去任何想去的地方
Once you finish this Give Back thing, you can go anywhere.
-做任何想做的事  -拜托  海莉
- You can do anything. - Come on, Haley.
我想和你一起做那些事
I want to do those things with you.
和別人一起吧
Do them with someone else.
不
No.
絕不
Never.
我和埃米的關系  很成熟
Me and Amir, it's... a mature relationship.
我很喜歡  我不知道你會不會喜歡
I like it. I don't know how much it would suit you.
雖然我們不會每周末都去俱樂部玩
But, you know, we don't go out clubbing every weekend.
但我們會存錢  我們去飯店吃飯
We... we save up for things, we go to restaurants,
有時聊聊書什么的
sometimes we talk about books.
聽著都無聊
That does sound shit.
我愛你  海莉
I love you, Haley.
我害怕失去你
I'm scared to be on my own.
來抱抱
Come here.
你會沒事的  好嗎
You'll be fine, OK?
我知道
Yeah.
我們有過愉快時光  對吧
Hey, we did have fun, didn't we?
老天  超級贊
Oh, my God, the best.
我忘了
I forgot.
我忘記打針了  海莉
I missed the shots, Haley.
拜托盡量快點過來  加里
Please get here as quick as you can, Gary.
他要變成僵尸了
He's turning now.
-求你了  -我來了  海莉
- Please! - I'm coming, Haley!
求你了  有人聽見嗎
Please, can anyone hear me?
-快放我出去  -海莉
- Please, get me out! - Haley!
它卡住了
It's jammed!
海莉  沒事的  我馬上把你弄出來
Haley, it's all right. I'm going to get you out of there!
海莉
Haley!
拿過去
Take it.
求你了
Please.
動手吧
Do it.
-你好  - "小潔在嗎"
- Hello. - "Is Jem there?"
加里
Gary.
抱歉  她不在
Yeah, she's not here.
"跟她說
"Tell her
"弗雷迪·普雷斯頓在車庫  快狂暴了
"Freddie Preston's turning rabid in his lock-up
"海莉被困在里面"
"and Haley's trapped inside."
誰來幫幫我
Somebody help!
救命啊
Help!
動手啊
Do it!
埃米  救救我
Amir, help me!
快點  他會殺了她的  快點
Quick. He'll kill her. Come on.
讓開
Away!
拜托  快點
Come on, quick.
開車
Come on!
求你了
Please
弗雷迪  弗雷迪
Freddie! Freddie!
住手
Stop!
-沒事了  -真是漂亮
- It's all right. - Nice one.
-沒事了  沒事了  看我  -海莉
- It's all right. It's all right, look. - Haley!
看我  別這樣  看著我
Look. Stop. Look at me.
看著我  沒事了  沒關系的
Look at me. It's fine. It's OK.
沒關系的  我們都一樣
It's OK. We're the same.
一邊去
One side!
加里  你在做什么
Gary, what are you doing?
他不舒服  需要接受藥物
He's down, he just needs his medication.
他沒打針時候  就應該料到現在了
Should have thought of that before he skipped it.
讓我給他注射  很快就沒事了
Just let me give him his dose and he'll be fine.
快點  我是你的話早行動了
Off you go, then. I'd get a move on, if I were you.
我今天被僵尸搞得很不爽
Today has been one of those days with me and rotters.
什么事都干得出來
Anything's liable to happen.
加里
Gary...
好了
Ok.
搞定了
There it is.
看到沒  他還沒有徹底轉變
See? He's not far gone.
他會沒事的
He'll be OK.
手腳輕一點
Whoa, take it easy.
管你怎么說
Whatever you say.
你要對他做什么
What are you going to do with him?
先關起來  會有人過來接他走
Put him in the lock-up. Someone will drop by,
明早再送去強制拘留中心
take him to the non-compliant detention centre in t'morning.
我聽說那是個好地方
I hear it's nice there.
剛才只是意外  他什么都沒有做
It was an accident. He didn't do anything.
你不能這樣
You can't do that.
我對你同類能做的事  會讓你目瞪口呆
You'll be amazed at what I can do to your sort,
你卻拿我無可奈何
and what you can do sod all about.
準備好了
Brace yourself.
小潔
Jem.
在嗎  小潔
Hey, Jem.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我過來看看你
I came to see how you're doing.
不  你不能待在這  我認真的
No. You have to go. I mean it.
你剛才打電話有什么事
Why did you phone earlier?
弗雷德·普雷斯頓變僵尸了
Freddie Preston turned rabid.
我可以搞定
Nothing I couldn't handle.
只不過  我希望你能在我身邊
I just wished you'd been along, though.
-我辦不到  抱歉  -不  你辦得到
- I can't, sorry. - Yeah, you can.
那事發生之后  就不行了
Not after what happened.
你當然可以
Of course you can.
每次我拿起槍  就有壞事發生
Bad things happen when I pick up a gun.
壞事時刻有
They happen anyway.
為什么你不會困擾  加里
How can you not be bothered, Gaz?
我殺了亨利
I killed Henry.
你焚毀了他的尸體
You burned his body.
我清楚
I know I did.
味道很不好
And it stunk.
像剛燒起來的篝火  記得那個味道嗎
Like t'bonfires first time round. Remember that smell?
鉆進鼻子里  幾天都不散
Got in your nose. Smell it for days after.
你怎么看這件事呢
How did you feel about it?
我們沒得選
We had no choice.
這次也一樣
Same with this.
我們是戰士  得互相照顧彼此
We're soldiers. We watch each other's backs.
但這不是全部
But that's not all of it.
我不會讓他們把你從我身邊搶走
I'm not having 'em take you away from me, all right?
給你帶了這個
I got you this.
怎么了  出了什么事
What's the matter? What happened?
吉倫
Kieren?
一旦下定決心
If we are serious...
要來不及去教堂了
You're late for church.
首先要丟開的  是我們的羞恥感
the first shackle we have to throw off is shame.
你可以很偉大
You could be great...
如果你能  哪怕只做兩秒鐘的正常人
if you could just be a normal person for two seconds.
*感覺對了  懶得管了*
*This feels right and I'm letting it*
*現在明白  該如何走*
*Now I know just what to do... *
知道諾頓村的半死癥患者妓院嗎
Did you know there was a PDS brothel in Roarton?
*親愛的  你若厭倦我*
*Tire of me if you will, my dear*
強烈抵制半死癥賣淫者
現在是存亡的關鍵時期
We're at a crucial point now.
真正的危機出現了  我們得保護好自己
There are real dangers and we need to protect ourselves.
*在我眼中  世界如此*
*This is the world as I see it now*
*公平正直  蕩然無存*
*It turns out that nothing is fair... *
-太過分了  爸爸  -吉倫  別這樣
- That crossed the line, Dad! - Kieren, please...
不要  他們坐在一邊  相互慶祝
No, while they sit around and get to high-five each other
把我們殺死  還當笑話一樣
about killing us like it's a big joke!
*親愛的  如你所愿  離我遠去*
*Leave me if you wish, my love*
*我卻依舊  留在原地*
*But I'm not going anywhere... *